<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Learn about Web Accessibility</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Learn about Web Accessibility</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Web Accessibility Matters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/baskin-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/baskin-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Making the web accessible ensures that everyone regardless of ability can navigate, understand, and interact with digital content.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-accessibility-is-essential&#34;&gt;Why Accessibility Is Essential&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Web accessibility allows people with visual, auditory, motor, or cognitive impairments to use websites with equal access. When developers design with accessibility in mind, the web becomes more usable for &lt;strong&gt;everyone&lt;/strong&gt;, not just people with disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This website highlights and demonstrates several important accessibility principles:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alternative Text&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Keyboard Navigation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Light &amp;amp; Dark Modes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Resizable Text&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Color Contrast&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Screen Readers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To explore these examples in depth, see the extended guide in the next article.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Essential Web Accessibility Examples and Why They Matter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/franzen-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/franzen-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Accessibility improves digital experiences by ensuring that websites can be used by people with a wide range of disabilities including visual, auditory, cognitive, and motor impairments. Below are several key accessibility features, why they matter, and how they support inclusive design.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;alternative-text&#34;&gt;Alternative Text&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternative text (alt text) provides written descriptions for images so users who rely on screen readers can understand visual content.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It is also important when an image fails to load or when users browse with assistive tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
